Abhijeet A Darfalkar

Flat no-09 3rd flr, Shrikanth View Residency.

Building no.S2, sr no-16/1/9. Satara Road,

Bh Bharatividyapith, Ambegaon Pathar, Pune. - 411046

Email Id: abhijeet darfalkar@yahoo.co.in.

Mob: 9850260855.

#### **OBJECTIVE: -**

A position in a results- oriented company that seeks an ambitious and career conscious person, where acquired skills and education will be utilized towards continues growth and advancement.

### **STRENGTHS:** -

• Functional knowledge in Under Writing in finance Industry.

- Have a good ability to learn on job, flexible, goal oriented and a team player.
- Details oriented person with strong organizational abilities.
- Have a good exposure to credit analysis.
- Quality oriented person and activity involved in process improvement.

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY: -**

Total 17 years of experience in banking industry Specialized in credit analysis, assigning appropriate risk ratings, good understating of credit appraisal of Unsecured & secured loans. Working mainly for commercial lending companies these professionals undertake and disburse the following activities mentioned on the resume below.

#### **SKILL SUMMARY: -**

Credit appraisal	Assigning appropriate risk rating & take the prudent Decision, collection management.
Fraud detection	Through various techniques (RCU, BSV), to check authentication of financial papers.
Formulating and preparing MIS	Preparing various MIS on monthly basis.

#### **PROFESSIONAL WORK HISTORY: -**

Presently engaged with Profectus capital Pvt ltd as Area Credit Manager at Pune for Mortgage loans.

DURATION: - From 9 jan 2023 to till date.

- Apprising of all mortgage (LAP) & Business loans (SME) Secured & Unsecured loans For Pune & ROM additional location.
- Understanding and projecting the future financial position of the borrower.
- Take prudent lending decisions based on sound judgment.
- Customer interaction through personal discussion.
- Complete Financial Analysis, Key ratios and cash flows of reported financials of the borrower.

- Ensure healthy branch portfolio –Responsible for the collations.
- People Management Handling the CPA team.
- Business visit and Verification-business verification, property visits.
- Responsible for pre disbursement Property Documents scrutiny as per legal search report.
- Case decisions through Valuation & legal Report.

### Previously y engaged with Poonawalla Fincorp Itd as Area Credit Manager at Pune. DURATION: - From 23 Sep 2019 to till 6 Jan2023.

- Credit appraisal /financial analysis of applicants Professional loans, BL & SME customers.
- Having experience in Digital lending in all over India locations
- Assessing the financial risk involved in the proposed cases before granting the loans proposals.
- Recommending sanctions Underwriting of cases & Take lending decisions.
- Customer interaction through personal discussion.
- Portfolio Quality & collection Management & providing support to business teams.
- Taking responsibility for researching borrowers and industries; completing annual reviews, identifying policy exceptions; discussing risk ratings and determining the acceptable credit amount with credit approvers.
- Team People & vendors Management.

# Previously engaged with Magma Fincorp ltd as Area Credit Manager at Pune. DURATION: - From 27June -2018 To 21 Sep 2019

- Under writing of cases & Take lending decisions for the locations Pune, Ahmednagar, Kolhapur, Satara, Sangali, Baramati locations.
- Business visit and Verification of cases.
- Assess credit worthiness of the self-employed –BL & SME customers.
- Take prudent lending decisions based on sound judgment.
- Customer interaction through personal discussion.
- Portfolio Quality & collection Management.
- Team People Management.

# Shriram City Union Finance Ltd as Assistant Manager for Credit at Pune. (Loan against property & Business Ioans (SME)

DURATION: - From 1Nov -2013 to 26 June2018.

- Apprising of all mortgage (LAP) & Business loans (SME) Secured & Unsecured loans For Pune, Kolhapur & Aurangabad additional location.
- Understanding and projecting the future financial position of the borrower.
- Take prudent lending decisions based on sound judgment.
- Customer interaction through personal discussion.
- Complete Financial Analysis, Key ratios and cash flows of reported financials of the horrower.
- Ensure healthy branch portfolio –Responsible for the collations.

- People Management Handling the CPA team.
- Business visit and Verification-business verification, property visits.
- Responsible for predisbursment Property Documents scrutiny as per legal search report.
- Case decisions through Valuation & legal Report.

# HDB Financial Services as Credit Relationship Manager at Ahmednagar. (Loan against property, personal loans, UCL & Gold Loan)

### **DURATION: - 28 May 2011 TO 31 Oct 2013.**

- Under writing of cases & Business visit and Sanction & Recommendation of cases.
- Products handled Loan against property, personal loans & Gold Loan & UCL.
- Assess credit worthiness of the self employed & salaried customers.
- Take prudent lending decisions based on sound judgment.
- Customer interaction through personal discussion.
- Portfolio Quality Collection Management.
- People Management.
- Assist CM with coordinating / managing RCU & verification vendors.
- Contribute to branch profit goals.
- Responsible for predisbusment Property Documents scrutiny as per legal.
- Also looking operation part ie disbursement process, PDD and collections updating.

# Fullerton India credit company Ltd as a credit Manager IN SME & BL. DURATION: - 1March 2011 TO 27 May 2011

- Credit appraisal /financial analysis of applicants.
- Evolution of financial risk involved in the proposed cases.
- Products Handled are Business loans.
- Recommending sanctions of business loans.
- System checking of account details.
- Formulating and preparing MIS on monthly basis.
- Taking personal interviews of prospective customer.

#### India bulls securities ltd as a compliance officer at Pune.

#### **DURATION: - 1 Feb 2006 TO 27 Feb 2011**

- Handle finance and accounts related functions.
- Recording of trade transactions of derivative settlements on daily basis.
- To follow up and comply with the SEBI AND RBI guidelines.
- Responsible for all compliance related matters.
- To coordinate with RMS department of HO for the margin calls.
- Responsible for broker confirmation.

#### ICICI BANK LTD as a credit officer in personal loan division Pune. (I-Process)

**DURATION: - 21 DEC 2004 TO 24 JAN 06.** 

- Assigning appropriate risk rating, preparing the cam etc.
- Products Handled Are Business loans.
- Evolution of financial risk involved in the proposed cases.
- Fraud detection.
- Appraisal of cases by ratio analysis.
- System checking of account details.
- Formulating and preparing MIS on monthly basis.
- Taking personal interviews of prospective customer.

# Initially Worked with Standard Chartered Bank as a Credit reviver in housing loan division Pune. (PAMAC)

### **DURATION: - 20 Aug 2003 TO 16 DEC 2004**

- Credit appraisal /financial analysis of applicants.
- Products Handled Are Housing loans.
- Evolution of financial risk involved in the proposed cases.
- Recommending sanctions.
- Preparing L2 /L3 approvals.
- Formulating and preparing MIS.
- Formulating and keeping track of TAT.

#### **Educational summary:**

Level	Course	Institution.	Passing year	Percentage
Post-Graduation	MBA (Finance	Shivaji	2003	64%
	Management)	University of		
		Kolhapur.		
Graduation	B.A.	Shivaji	2001	57%
		University of		
		Kolhapur.		

Computer Literacy: - Passed 'MS-CIT' Exam of M.K.C.L. Working knowledge of **excel**, PowerPoint, words etc.

### Personal Information: -

Name:Abhijeet Ashokrao DarfalkarEmail Id:abhijeet darfalkar@yahoo.co.in.

Languages Known : English, Hindi, Marathi.

Current location : Pune Marital status : Married.